Guide to the Civil war papers, 1861-1912
Department of Special Collections
Civil war papers,
1861-1912
Special Collections M0284
3 folders
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
1. Gift of Mrs. Robert Young, 1976. 2. Provenance unknown. 3. Bequest of Leila Glenn Saunders, 1980.
Scope and Content
Civil war period materials including: 1. Richard Reynolds papers, 1861-1912. (Notices to report, appointments, honorable discharges, pension notices, and loyalty oath). 2. A manuscript by Edward H. Ripley titled, "Memories of the capture and occupation of Richmond, April 3 1865," 1885. 49 p. 3. John N. Manlove, letter signed to "dear sister," 1864 Apr. 14.
Container List
- Richard Reynolds Papers. Gift of Mrs Robert Young. (Folder 1:)
  - 1861, July 9.Honorable discharge of Richard Reynolds, Private, from Indiana Volunteers State Service., Item 1.
  - 1865, July 7,Notice to R. Reynolds to report to mustering out from U.S. Service., Item 2.
  - 1865, August 2,Discharge of Richard Reynolds from Company J, 23rd Regiment of Indiana Volunteers., Item 3.
  - 1912, August 14,Honorable Discharge of Harold A. Reynolds from Kansas National Guard., Item 4.
  - 1879, September 1,Arrears of Pension notice for Richard Reynolds., Item 5.
  - 1878, September 3,Pension Office, Dept. of Interior notice of $2/month pension commencing 14 June 1877., Item 6.
  - 1879, January 23,Dept. of Interior Pension. Notice of Issue of Cert. #155180 to Richard Reynolds., Item 7.
  - 1885, July 27,Dept. of Interior Pension Office. Notice of Cert. #155180 for increase pension for Richard Reynolds., Item 8.
  - 1888, March 4 - June 4,Voucher to receive pension of Richard Reynolds., Item 9.
  - 1887, November 16,Dept. of Interior, Pension Office. Notice of increase pension., Item 10.
  - 1888, April 25,Voucher for Accrued Pension. Richard Reynolds widow Mary R. Reynolds applying., Item 11.
  - 1861, July 27,Appointment of Richard Reynolds to Sergeant in Company I, 23rd Regiment, Indiana Foot Volunteers., Item 12.
  - 1864, January 5,Official Promotion Papers of Richard Reynolds to Sergeant, Company II, 23rd Regiment of Ind. Veteran Volunteers. In red ink over printed certificate record of battles Reynolds engaged in. On verso recommendation for promotion for Duty performed inside Enemy lines, Item 13.
  - 1863, December 31,Application for reimbursement for rations while James Gosgriff was on furlough 1 Dec. 1863 to 31 Dec. 1863. Unsigned, Undated., Item 14.
  - 1864, September 3,ALS Wm. B. C. Schlater (Col. A.D.C.) to Sgt. R. Reynolds., Item 15.
  - 1864, October 28,Special Orders No. 72 enabling Richard Reynolds, Sergeant, to proceed on furlough despite loss of proper papers due to robbery. Issued by Hdqtrs. 2d Brig., 3d Div., 15th A.C., Item 16.
  - 1864, October 28,Oath of Richard Reynolds affirming receipt of furlough and robbery of same., Item 17.
  - 1865, January 2,Loyalty Oath to U.S.A. by R. Reynolds. Witnessed by S.J. Mofinger., Item 18.
  - 1865, August 2,ALS Blake's Law & Military Claim Office. Indianapolis. Receipt of discharge with application for arrears of pay from Richard Reynolds., Item 19.
  - 1868, February 19,Receipt of $6.33 taxes from Richard Reynolds to Charleston, Clark City, Ind. Treasurer's Office., Item 20.
- Reply, Edward H. Memories/The capture and occupation of Richman of Apr. 3 1865typescript, 1885. Provenance unknown. (Folder 2)
- 1864 Apr 14ALS to clear sister from John N. Manlove, describing Civil war battles. Bequest of Leila Glenn Saunders, 1980. (Folder 3)
  Contact person: Mrs. Roy Madson